Guide to the Ved Mehta Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- March 2005 Acquisition, circa 1952-2005; 23.48; (52 boxes) + 3 broadside folders
  - Writings and Research Files
    - Remembering Mr. Shawn's New Yorker
      - Draft, third version, 2001 January 15; 3 (Box 158)
    - All for Love
      - Bills, 1968-1969; 3 (Box 158)
      - Bills (continued), 1968-1969; 3 (Box 159)
      - Lyrics of "Guantanamera", 1998 September 24 (Box 159)
      - Biblical quote, road to Damascus (Box 159)
      - Gigi checking (Box 159)
      - Gigi/ Mimi, 1999 (Box 159)
      - Letter to "My dear Arthur", 1967 March 10 (Box 159)
      - Pomona materials, not used (Box 159)
      - Gigi notes on "Fandango," by Antonio Soler (Box 159)
      - Information on Carl Binger from daughter Kilty (Box 159)
      - Lord of Misrule (Box 159)
      - Megan song lyrics (Box 159)
      - J.D. Salinger/duckpond (Box 159)
      - Shrady Christmas/ notes from phone conversation (Box 159)
      - Muriel Spark's "The Driver's Seat" (Box 159)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 159)
      - Book proposal (Box 159)
      - Vivaldi's "Spring" (Box 159)
      - Reference (Box 159)
      - Translations (Box 159)
      - Dr. Bak, 3 (Box 159)
      - Correspondence, 2001-2002; 3 (Box 159)
      - Correspondence, 2001; 2 (Box 160)
      - Draft, Carol Anderson's copy, 1999 February; 4 (Box 160)
      - Gigi and Jeremy, undated (Box 160)
      - India bills, 3 (Box 160)
      - India bills, 8 (Box 161)
      - Checking (Box 161)
      - Ved's letters to Daddy, 1964-1970 (copies), 1996 (Box 161)
    - Dark Harbor
      - Checking, 2 (Box 161)
      - Checking-field visits, 2 (Box 161)
      - Dutch edition (Box 161)
      - Draft, first 51 pages, undated (Box 161)
      - Correspondence, 1982, undated (Box 161)
      - Correspondence, 1982, undated; 2 (Box 162)
      - Correspondence, 2001-2002; 3 (Box 162)
      - Correspondence, 2003; 2 (Box 162)
      - Catalogue copy and related correspondence, 2002 (Box 162)
      - Checking and miscellaneous material (Box 162)
      - Publicity, 2003; 2 (Box 163)
      - Publicity tour, 3 (Box 163)
    - The Red Letters
      - Father's love letters, edited and typed, 2 (Box 163)
      - Father's love letters, edited, revised, retyped (Box 164)
      - Father's love letters, computer print outs and Daddyji's commentary (Box 164)
      - Insert love letters and Daddyji's illness (Box 164)
      - Red Letters, including Ved's correspondence with his father (Box 164)
      - Daddyji reference material (Box 164)
      - Mohammad Sleem (Box 164)
      - Questionable facts 1959 (Box 164)
      - Benjamin Franklin lectures, 1974 (Box 164)
      - Daddyji's Deputy Director General 1949, miscellaneous notes and corrections by father (Box 164)
      - Later Mrs. Clyde (Box 164)
      - Answers to queries on love letters (Box 164)
      - India departure (Box 164)
      - "O" short story (Box 164)
      - Notes on love letters, 1967-1978 (Box 164)
      - "Different version? of love letters from the file cabinet" (Box 164)
      - Draft (selection), "somewhat revised with D's comments inserted" (Box 165)
      - Checking: Ashok matrimonial (Box 165)
      - Later volumes (Box 165)
      - Photographs (Box 165)
      - Father's memoir, original correspondence, 1970-1972; 2 (Box 165)
      - Mamaji and second visit abroad 1967 (Box 165)
      - Mamaji's illness 1986-1987 (Box 165)
      - Mamaji 1970s (miscellaneous notes, corrections by Father) (Box 165)
      - Mamaji's health 1970s, (miscellaneous notes, corrections by Father) (Box 165)
      - Mamaji 1976: Dr. Frankland, 1983 (Box 165)
      - Usha circa 1970 (miscellaneous notes, corrections by Father) (Box 165)
      - Autobiographical chapter, checking (Box 165)
      - A-series reference, chronology 1974, Mala's wedding (Box 165)
      - Family appellations: Chachaji (miscellaneous notes, corrections by Father) (Box 165)
      - New material (miscellaneous notes, corrections by Father) (Box 165)
      - Autobiography letter to Pitaji, 1966 (copy) (Box 165)
      - Father's files reference for chronology, Ved's visit to India, 1972 (Box 165)
      - Simla picnic, 1933 (miscellaneous notes, corrections by Father), undated (Box 165)
      - Partition Daddyji's ancestor's, 1947 (miscellaneous notes, corrections by Father), undated (Box 165)
      - Partition Bakshi Tek Chand's view, 1947 (miscellaneous notes, corrections by Father), undated (Box 165)
      - Bhaji Ganga Ram Partitian, 1947 (miscellaneous notes, corrections by Father), undated (Box 165)
      - Mussoorie, 1959, undated (Box 165)
      - Daulat Ram's memoir, 1959, undated (Box 165)
      - Daddyji and Mamaji, 1960s-1980s, undated (Box 165)
      - Babuji will, 1972, undated (Box 166)
      - 21 December 1974 (miscellaneous notes, corrections by Father), undated (Box 166)
      - 6 February 1975 (miscellaneous notes, corrections by Father), undated (Box 166)
      - Father's diaries, 1949 -1972 (copies), undated; 5 (Box 166)
      - Father's telephone book (copy), undated; 2 (Box 166)
      - For ninth volume: Babuji and Bhaji Ganga Ram 1946-1957, undated (Box 166)
      - Autobiographical series, correspondence active, 1973-1984 (Box 166)
      - Daddyji's later material, 1974, undated (Box 166)
      - Father's passports, 2 (Box 166)
      - Narrative: travel to California 1952, undated (Box 166)
      - Daddy making friends, 1952 June (Box 166)
      - Mrs. Clyde 1970-1978, undated, 9 (Box 166)
      - Correspondence from Father's files, 1964-1974; 11 (Box 166)
      - Publicity, 2 (Box 167)
      - Checking (Box 167)
      - Correspondence, 2001-2004, undated; 3 (Box 167)
    - Correspondence about books
      - Correspondence: The ledge between the streams, Easton Press edition (Box 167)
      - Mahatma Gandhi translations (Box 167)
      - Mr. Shawn, 1974-1984; 2 (Box 167)
      - Portrait of India, 1968-1971; 3 (Box 168)
      - Up at Oxford, 2003 (Box 168)
  - Financial Papers
    Boxes 169-183 (Financial Papers): Restricted until 2031.
    - Earnings from writings, etc., 1963-1977; 27 (Box 169)
    - Earnings from writings, etc. (continued), 1978-1987; 44 (Box 170)
    - Maine bills and financial records, 1982-1985 April; 33 (Box 171)
    - Maine bills and financial records, 1985 May-1986; 23 (Box 172)
    - Maine bills and financial records, 1987-1988; 27 (Box 173)
    - Maine bills and financial records, 1989-1990; 26 (Box 174)
    - Maine bills and financial records, 1991-1992 November; 25 (Box 175)
    - Maine bills and financial records, 1992 December-1994 July; 22 (Box 176)
    - Maine bills and financial records, 1994 August-1996; 32 (Box 177)
    - Maine bills and financial records, 1997-1999 July; 31 (Box 178)
    - Maine bills and financial records, 1999 August-2000; 17 (Box 179)
    - Maine bills and financial records, 2002-; 12 (Box 180)
    - Bank check records, 1998-2003; 6 (Box 180)
    - Awning, 1992 (Box 181)
    - Future projects, 1994; 2 (Box 181)
    - Heating (Box 181)
    - Swimming pool, 1988-2002; 2 (Box 181)
    - Repairs, 2002 (Box 181)
    - New wing, 1993-2002; 3 (Box 181)
    - Landscaping, 1994-2002; 2 (Box 181)
    - Maintenance, 2004 (Box 181)
    - New buildings, Leach brothers, legal, 1990; 2 (Box 181)
    - Knights problem (new building), 1989 (Box 182)
    - Basement problem, 1991-2000 (Box 182)
    - Conversion to Al's Heating, 1999-2001 (Box 182)
    - Forest management and stewardship, 1994-1995; 2 (Box 182)
    - Future construction, 1992 (Box 182)
    - Dark Harbor construction photographs, circa 1984; 3 (Box 182)
    - Bank of New York, 2003; 12 (Box 183)
  - Speaking engagements
    - Speaking engagements, 1959-1988; 11 (Box 184)
    - Speaking engagements, 1989-1999; 19 (Box 185)
    - Speaking engagements, 2001-2003; 4 (Box 186)
  - Subject Files
    - Appointments (Box 187)
    - Articles, 1997-2003; 4 (Box 187)
    - Articles: Babuji correspondence with Storie magazine, 2003 (Box 187)
    - Bill Borders, The New India (Box 187)
    - Contemporary Authors, 2002-2003; 7 (Box 187)
    - Correspondence: England inactive, 1994-2003; 12 (Box 187)
    - Correspondence: United States inactive, 1994-1998; 7 (Box 187)
    - Correspondence: United States inactive, 1999-2004; 13 (Box 188)
    - Correspondence: India inactive, 1997-2000; 4 (Box 188)
    - Correspondence: Israel inactive, 1993 (Box 188)
    - Correspondence: elsewhere inactive, 1988-2000; 7 (Box 188)
    - Correspondence: elsewhere, 2001-2002 (Box 189)
    - Correspondence: family, 1986-2004; 10 (Box 189)
    - Correspondence: fan mail, 1996-2004; 4 (Box 189)
    - Correspondence: miscellaneous (Box 189)
    - Honors (Box 189)
    - Immigration: old passports, 1949-1995; 6 (Box 189)
    - Interview: Paris Review, 1993-1995; 3 (Box 189)
    - New Yorker contracts, 1961-2004; 4 (Box 190)
    - New York Institute for the Humanities (Box 190)
    - New York Public Library (Box 190)
    - Newhouse problem-office assistant (Box 190)
    - Preview port (Box 190)
    - Time Asia correspondence and contract, 2003 (Box 190)
    - Time Asia- Diaspora-checking, 2003; 2 (Box 190)
    - Remembering Mr. Shawn's New Yorker: Milton Greenstein correspondence (Box 190)
    - Remembering Mr. Shawn's New Yorker: Gottlieb, 2 (Box 190)
    - Remembering Mr. Shawn's New Yorker: blueprints for new offices, 1990 (Box 190)
    - Remembering Mr. Shawn's New Yorker: Tina Brown, 2 (Box 190)
    - David Remmick (Box 190)
  - Fellowships
    - Guggenheim (Box 190)
    - Hazen (Box 190)
    - MacArthur, 2 (Box 190)
    - Academic (Box 190)
    - Rockefeller (Box 190)
    - American Foundation for the Blind (Box 190)
    - Balliol (Box 190)
    - Boston University (Box 190)
    - Center for Advanced Studies, 2 (Box 190)
    - Center for Advanced Studies (Box 191)
    - Ford (Box 191)
    - Freedom Forum (Box 191)
    - Media Studies Center, Freedom Forum, 1996-1997 (Box 191)
    - Correspondence: fellowship applications, 1970-2000; 3 (Box 191)
    - Festival of Letters, 2002 (Box 191)
  - Miscellaneous papers and muniments
    - Yale -- Benno Schmidt (Box 191)
    - Yale -- New Haven house (Box 191)
    - Photos with Cuomo (Box 191)
    - Who's Who in America certificate (Box 191)
    - White House (Box 191)
    - Miscellaneous papers and degree certificates, 10 (Box 191)
    - The Company Store: shipping receipt, 2005 January 24 (Box 191)
  - Oversize muniments
    - Miscellaneous awards and degree certificates, 1951-1995; 5 (Box 192)
    - Miscellaneous awards and degree certificates, 1988-2004; 2 (Box 193)
  - Architectural plans
    - Architectural plans for house in Dark Harbor, Maine (Box 194 Broadside)
    - Architectural plans for house in Dark Harbor, Maine (Box 195 Broadside)
    - Architectural plans for house in Dark Harbor, Maine (Box 196 Broadside)
  - Formerly Restricted Papers
    Boxes 197-198: Open for research. Restriction expired in 2011.
    - Duplicates: Kumar, Lalita, circa 1995; 2 (Box 197)
    - Bills from E. Kronzek, computer printout, undated (Box 197)
    - Kumar expenses, computer printout, undated (Box 197)
    - Kumar itinerary and bills 1966 (copies), undated (Box 197)
    - Duplicate Lalita material (copies), undated; 2 (Box 197)
    - Kumar checking (copies), undated; 2 (Box 197)
    - Correspondence about Lalita (copies), undated (Box 197)
    - Lalita material (original), typescript, corrected, 1974 (Box 197)
    - Lalita material (carbon), typescript carbon, corrected, 1974 (Box 197)
    - Lalita material (copy), typescript, corrected (copy), undated (Box 197)
    - Correspondence: Kumar, Lalita, 1966-1968 (Box 197)
    - Harvard pages taken out of the New Yorker Book, computer printout, corrected, undated (Box 197)
    - Oma overflow material, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 197)
    - Father's letters, 8 (Box 198)
  - Restricted Papers
    Boxes 199-200: Restricted until 2031.
    - Engagement Diaries, 1990-1998; 8 (Box 199)
      Restricted until 2031
    - Restricted papers, 5 (Box 200)
      A folder listing of restricted papers is filed in the box.
- April 2011 Acquisition, 1960s-2011; 13.09; (15 boxes)
  - Files from Mehta's study
    - Book royalty information, some clippings and material directly associated with Continents of Exile., 1973-2011 (Box 201)
    - Diaspora correspondence, club information, and other papers, 1990s-2000s (Box 202)
    - Materials related to speeches and television and radio appearances, 1978-1979 (Box 203)
    - Articles, biographical material, All For Love correspondence, fan letters, lecture material, information on a J.D. Salinger documentary (2006), files related to speaking engagements, and a file on unpublished stories, 1990s-2009 (Box 204)
  - Files stored in a closet
    - Correspondence and other papers related to Mehta's writings, as well as family papers, wedding information, and expired passports, 1960s-2000s (Box 205)
  - Files stored in a basement storage unit
    - Papers related to articles and book royalties, as well as various clubs, international correspondence, fan mail, and invitations, 2000-2008 (Box 206)
    - Correspondence, travel material concerning various international trips, and writings, 1980s-2007 (Box 207)
    - Publisher files, various published and unpublished articles, material related to Continents of Exile, and files regarding Mehta's Vieques property, 1998-2008 (Box 208)
    - Correspondence and manuscripts relating to Dark Harbor and Widow's Son, 2000s (Box 209)
    - Vassar, Yale, and inactive teaching files, 1985-1990s (Box 210)
    - Yale teaching files, 1990s (Box 211)
    - Correspondence and invitations, 1960s-2007 (Box 211)
    - Diaries, 1999-2006 (Box 212)
    - Photocopies, some from previous accessions of Mehta's papers, 2000s (Box 213)
    - Checkbooks, 1961-1983 (Box 214)
    - Checkbooks, 1961-1980 (Box 215)
    - Organizational chart outlining the original in situ distribution of files within Ved Mehta's home., circa 2011 (Box 215)